# Terry O'Keefe

(715) 243-4450 terryjamesokeefe@gmail.com github.com/TerryOKeefe

# **Summary**

Project-focused Full Stack Software Engineer with extensive background in various coding languages, developing applications, and building websites from the ground up. Specializes in JavaScript and React. Professional strengths include creative problem-solving, written and verbal communication, and time management. Detail-oriented mindset from 10+ years of experience in the retail management industry.

# **Skills**

JavaScript (React, Redux, Redux-Saga), C#, .NET, Node, Express, jQuery, SQL (PostgreSQL), Git, HTML, CSS, Material-UI, Bootstrap, Agile, Back End, json, REST, Deployment, Unit Testing, Design, Operating Systems (Windows, MacOS), IT Support, Computer Networking, Self-Motivated, Collaboration, Problem Solving, Decision Making, Communication, Customer Service, Leadership & Management, Adaptability, Budgeting & Forecasting, Motivation & Support

# **Experience**

February 2021 - Current

**Project Highlights** - Full-Stack Software Engineer Student

- Solo Project: MN Brew
  - Developed to help brewers with small batch kit brewing.
  - Allow users to digitally store brew recipes and share with other users.
  - o React, Redux-Saga, Node, Express, PostgreSQL, Material-UI, HTML, CSS
- Client Project: Barktique & Meow
  - Client is looking to simplify their business to business integration with Weebly.
  - Collaborated remotely with three developers to build and implement an order processing application.
  - React, Redux-Saga, Node, Express, PostgreSQL, Nodemailer, AWS-S3, Material-UI, HTML, CSS

May 2020 - May 2021

### **Trafera**, Minneapolis - Laptop Technician

- Collaborated with team members to install hardware, image Operating System, test units, and prepare for shipping.
- Ensured top tier quality while maintaining specified goals.
- Adjusted work schedule to meet the increased product demand.
- Launched initial Standard Operating Procedures and facilitated training for new hires.

May 2016 - May 2020

### Walmart, Stillwater, MN - Assistant Store Manager

- Supervised multiple area managers and associates, analyzed areas of opportunities and brainstormed ways to improve.
- Achieved top 5 in the region on key metrics including sales, cleanliness, and customer satisfaction.
- Revamped Standard Operating Procedures and facilitated training throughout the 250+ employee organization on newly optimized business processes.

- Forecasted monthly Profit and Loss, communicating that data with teams.
- Partnered with vendors to get the products customers wanted.

January 2016 - May 2016

### Walmart, Vadnais Heights, MN - Store Remodel Assistant Manager

- Assisted third shift remodel projects to ensure zero downtime or interruption in sales.
- Collaborated with various project teams, adjusting plans as needed for the business.
- Monitored and managed budget allocation for projects.

November 2014 - January 2016

### Walmart, Stillwater, MN - Assistant Manager

- Revitalized underperforming retail areas.
- Aided in the retraining of teams to follow the company's best practices.
- Adapted to any changes presented by customers and associates.

February 2013 - November 2014

#### Walmart, Hudson, WI - Operation Zone Manager

- Communicated and clarified new processes to team members.
- Rejuvenated front end processes to increase productivity at registers.
- Orchestrated back room inventory refresh to streamline product coming in and out.

# **Education**

August 2021

#### Prime Digital Academy, Minneapolis, MN - Full Stack Software Engineering Certification

Professional Skills Practice, Professional development, Diversity, Equity & Inclusion Courses, Client work.

2005-2008

#### **University of Wisconsin-River Falls, River Falls, WI** - *Generals*

Generals and courses toward Chemistry and Biology.

## Certificates

May 2020

## **Google IT Support Certificate** - Coursera

Completed five-courses, developed by Google, that include hands-on, practice-based assessments. Competency in foundational skills, including troubleshooting and customer service, networking, operating systems, system administration, and security.

# **Community Involvement**

Relay For Life, Feeding America, Adopt a Highway, Service Animals